Side Flexion With Your Arms Overhead.
It's another exercise that's great for your middle area, for your obliques and your back extensors.
When you start in your standing position, you want to make sure that you tuck your hips in, so your back is straight.
Make sure that if you're not sure of what to do or if your back bothers you a little bit, make sure somebody watches your form because sometimes people tend to do this and you see how my shoulders are behind my hips.
That's going to hurt your back.
It's not a push forward, it's a tuck.
So, that's something to remember.
Now, your feet are going to be underneath hips, your knees are slightly bent, you keep that tucked back in your tummy, meaning take your belly button in, your arms are going overhead.
Be careful not to let the shoulders come up, so you really have to keep them down, pressing with the back muscles.
As you go down to the Side Flex, you're going to take an inhale, and when you come up you exhale.
Now notice how my head is going with the wrist of the spine.
You want to make sure that you don't just take the arms or let it all slump like this.
You want to make sure you keep your chest up and keep the head going with the rest of the spine.
You may want to look in the mirror and see your alignment, make sure that you are in total, in full alignment.
Or pay attention to your body.
Sometimes when you do this, if you're not doing it correctly, your back will let you know, it will hurt, or something will start bothering you.
That means that the body is letting you know that something is not right. So again, just keeping the arms overhead, shoulders down, inhale, exhale.
Do a feel.
Don't forget to keep the tuck, the minute you let the tuck, this is what's going to happen, not good for the back, so keep it right here.
Do same number on each side and you're ready to go, bikini time.
See you soon.